# Adaeze Ndupu

+2348132284088 | andupu4@gmail.com | Linkedin Profile

## Summary:

Adaeze Ndupu is a budding front-end developer with 3 years of experience converting still-life designs to interactive and responsive websites.

She is a problem solver and pursues user satisfaction from creating websites and products that provide solutions to companies or individuals

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript
- Frontend Development: React, Next.Js
- Version Control: Git/GitHub
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies
- Styling: Tailwind CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap
- Frameworks: Webflow, Wordpress

## **Professional Experience:**

Code Funhouse [Birmingham, England, United Kingdom] [October 2023 - Present]

- Frontend Developer:
  - Successfully migrated the existing codebase from React to Next.js, ensuring compliance with Next.js conventions and best practices.
  - Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement RESTful APIs, enhancing system interoperability.
  - Conducted a comprehensive codebase refactoring to eliminate code redundancy, leading to a more efficient and maintainable codebase.
  - Participated in Agile development methodologies, managing tasks through sprints and actively engaging in meetings to enhance the system's overall performance and functionality.

## Warehöuzit [Lagos, Nigeria] [Nov 2022 - Sep 2023]

- Lead Frontend Developer:
  - Developed and implemented user-friendly, responsive web interfaces using React, Tailwind and Next.js.
  - Collaborated with other developers, designers, and stakeholders to create visually appealing and functional websites
  - Conducted code reviews and quality assurance testing to ensure the website was free of errors, bugs, and inconsistencies.

• Conducted research on emerging web development trends, tools, and technologies to enhance the website's functionality and usability.

## **Education:**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Babcock University [Ilishan-Remo, Ogun] [June 2020]

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Algorithms, Web Development, Software Engineering

## **Certifications:**

- Frontend Web Developer (No code) Entry Level
- HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers Coursera
- Web Design and Development (Frontend) Side Hustle
- Intro to Programming Nanodegree Udacity
- Workflow Tools for Web Developers LinkedIn

## **Projects:**

- <u>GetLinkedAI Pre-Hackathon Website</u>: Developed a responsive website for the GetLinkedAI Pre-Hackathon using React, Next.Js, Tailwind and Framer Motion.
- <u>Youtube Clone</u>: Developed a clone on the basic features of the popular streaming platform, Youtube using React
- Gradient Swatch Website
- <u>Slack Homepage</u> Webflow
- <u>BlogosphereHub</u> Tailwind and React

## Portfolio:

- GitHub Profile
- Personal Website

## Volunteering

• Frontend Developer, CodeSpace (May 2023 - June 2023)

#### Languages:

• English (Native)

#### **Interests:**

- Open-source contributions
- Hackathons
- Games and Animes

## References:

Available upon request.